CURRICULUM VITAE

Name Mohammad Ahmad Address New Delhi, Delhi Telephone +91 8700916432

Email <u>md.ahmad0652@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn <u>www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-ahmad-02891415b</u>

Profile:

I am an undergrad pursuing B.Tech from Jamia Millia Islamia in Electronic and Communication Engineering. I have a major interest in programming and problem-solving. I have good knowledge of Machine Learning (And AI) and am interested in Research in ML or DL domains. I have done a good amount of projects (Listed Below) to support my skills. I also have good knowledge and experience in Web development (Both FrontEnd and Backend).

GitHub Account Link. GitLab Account Link.

Work Experience:

Innovaccer

- Worked on Telemed product with frontend on React.
- Integrating video calling feature using MS teams API.
- API and utility development on Django.

07/2019 - 10/2019 Software Developer Intern

Rydeu.com

Ground transport and logistics solution company based in Germany

- Worked on Database design and their migrations.
- Designed multiple API endpoints and their integration.
- Integrated many services like mailing, logging, stripe, etc.

12/2018 - 01/2019 **Web Developer Intern**

Al-Ghamdi Travels

New Delhi, Delhi

 Worked On Alghamdi Management Portal built on Node.js as Back-end and MongoDB as Databases.

Projects:

Code-ML (10/01/2020 - present)

A Machine Learning Blog, completely built from scratch. Since I had started learning ML and AI, I thought of sharing my knowledge. As we know, what is the best to learn and remember? is to teach others. It has almost all the features a traditional blog has like commenting, bookmark, likes, auth, etc.

Tech Stack - Node.js, React.js, Bootstrap, and PostgreSQL.

Face Recognition Using Tensorflow.is

A Web application to recognize faces and identify it, One can train it by entering the name and their pics in the browser, this is done by using Pre-trained model mobilenet_v1_1 from Tensorflow Hub. <u>Demo</u>

• Reddit Flair Detection

Detection of popular Reddit flair on "**r/india/**" subreddit. This project includes data scraping, EDA, modeling, and Heroku deployment.

Repository <u>link</u>.

Toxic Text Analysis Using Tensorflow.js

Web Application built on HTML, CSS, and javascript, which analyze toxicity in a given Text using a <u>Pre-trained model</u> from Tensorflow Hub. <u>Demo</u>

Mini Projects on Deep Learning:

- 1. Classifying Number by training MNIST data on Neural Network.
- 2. Classifying Cloths by training Fashion MNIST data on Neural Network.
- 3. Finger counting using the OpenCV library.
- 4. Video-based object detection using OpenCV.

Alexa Skills: Web Scraping project, Python

It is Alexa skill which uses its python SDK, in its core a python script run that scrapes data from Wikipedia. Second skill which tells users where they can visit in a particular city for that I scrape a huge Data of cities from websites and structured it in a way that my Alexa skill required. Link

Education/Qualifications:

2017-Present Jamia Millia Islamia, B.Tech Electronics and Communication Engineering (Currently Pursuing)

2014-2016 Dev Samaj Modern School No-1, Senior School Certificate Examination (Class 12), 90.04%

2012-2014 Dev Samaj Modern School No-2, Secondary School Examination (Class 10), 8.8 CGPA.

Skills: C++, JavaScript, Python, Node.js, SQL/NoSQL, Flask, React js, Machine Learning. **Frameworks/library:** Numpy, Pandas, Keras, Matplotlib, sci-kit- learn, OpenCV, Tensorflow, tensorflow.js.

Certificates:

- 1) Deep Learning Specialization
 - a) Learned about Deep and shallow Neural Networks.
 - b) Learned all about activation function, optimization, regularisation, etc.
 - c) Different strategies like dataset distribution, human-level performance, error analysis, etc.
 - d) CNN, different architects of CNN like leNet, googLeNet, etc. And some object detection algo like yolo, etc.
 - e) Learning about RNN, word embedding, sequence to sequence modeling, etc.
- 2) TensorFlow: Data and Deployment 4 course Specialization.
 - a) Learned how to save models and use them in web and mobile devices.
 - b) Learned about TensorFlow splits, tensorboard, and how to share pre-trained models with Tensorflow Hub.
 - c) And how to create a data pipeline using TensorFlow.
- 3) Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)

Languages: English, Hindi.

Interests: Programming, Video games, Table Tennis.